Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3 J. A. Fishman Lectures and Talks ca. 1940-1992
  - Subseries B Audio and Video Cassettes
    - (2)DER BAYTROG FUN VELTLEKHKAYT TSUM YIDISHN LEBN Y, copy 2 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - (4)YIDISHE NESIYES, YIDISHE MAKHSHOVES, Y, IIIA/12/28 side 3, 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - (3)YIDISHE NESIYES, YIDISHE MAKHSHOVES sides 1 & 2, Y, IIIA/12/28 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - (1)Interview with JAF in the Basque Country, E 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - (2) Cartoons About Language, E 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - (3) Post-Exilic Jewish Languages: Similarities and Differences, E, IIIA/9/3 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - (4) Post-Exilic Jewish Languages: Similarities and Differences, E, IIIA/9/3 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - (1) NOSN BIRNBOYM: TSIYONIST, YIDISHIST, AGUDIST, Y, IIIA/8/2 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (2) What is Happening to Spanish in the United States?, E, IIIA/12/14 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (3) BAGRISUNG-VORT TZU DR. MORDKHE SHAECHTER LEKOVED DOS AROYSLEBEN FUN ZAYNE DRAY BIKHER, Y, IIIA/1/15 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (4) DER BAYTROG FUN VELTLEKHKAYT TSUM YIDISHN LEBN, Y 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (5) Cartoons - NYU, E 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (6) VELTLEKHE YIDISHKAYT, Y 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (7) Ferguson Festschrift Presentation, E 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (8) BAYM NUSEKH-VILNE HASKORE, Y, IIIA/4/19 1986, (audiocassette) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - (1-6) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country), Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - (1-6) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country), Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - (1-6) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country), Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - (1-6) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country), Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - (1-5) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country, Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - (1-5) Conference Proceedings about the Basque Language (in the Basque country), Basque/Spanish/E 1986, (audiocassettes) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - (1) TBE or Not TBE Sociolinguistics and Education, E, IIIa/10/11 1987, (video cassette) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - (1) 1987 Summer Language Institute, Sacramento, CA, E 1987, (video cassette) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - (1) BAYM OYSTEYLN DI PREMYE TSU MORDKHE SHEKHTER, Y, IIIA/1/14 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - (2) BASKN ALEKHO SHPANYE, Y 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - (3) LANGUAGE POLICY FOR ENDANGERED LANGUAGES, E, IIIA/6/17 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - (4) NOSN BIRNBOYMS TSUGANG TSUM AMERIKANER YIDNTUM ONHEYB 20STN YORHUNDERT, Y, IIIA/8/5 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - (1) Party at Ferkauf Graduate School - Yeshiva University with Bilingual Students and Faculty, E/SP 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - (2) "English Official", E 1987, (audio and video cassettes) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - (3) TSI DARF AMERIKE AN OFITSYELE SHPRAKH ?, Y, IIIA/11/25 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - (1) The Odyssey of Nathan Birnbaum (NY), Y/E, IIIA/8/7 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - (2) Presentation at Basque Conference in San Sebastian, Spain, E 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - (3) English Only, E, IIIA/3/16 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - (4) The Odyssey of Nathan Birnbaum (Michigan), Y, IIIA/8/7 1987, (audiocassette) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - (1) International Perspectives of the Purported Debits of Linguistic Heterogeneity, E, IIIA/5/5 1988, (video cassette) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - (1) Dr. Fishman's Retirement Party, E/Sp 1988, (video cassette) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - (1) Dr. Fishman's Retirement Party Ferkauf Graduate School - Yeshiva University, E/Sp 1988, (video cassette) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - (1) SIMPOZIYUM VEGN DER TSHERNOVITSER KONFERENTS, Y 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (2) Yiddish: The New Generation, E 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (3) JAF Retirement Celebration at Ferkauf Graduate School - Yeshiva University, E/Sp 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (4) JAF reads first part of his article for the TZUFUNFT magazine: BIRNBAUMS DRAY KONFERENTSN, Y, IIIA/8/3 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (5) Commencement Address at Graduation Ceremonies of the Ferkauf Graduate School - Yeshiva University, E 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (6) Linguistic Heterogeneity: Civil Strife and Per Capita Gross National Product, E, IIIA/7/1 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - (1) VOS HOT DI YIDISHE LITERATUR GETON FAR DER YIDISHER SHPRAKH? Y, IIIA/12/5 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - (2) Maintenance and Loss of Minority Languages: Conference Summary, E, IIIA/7/3 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - (3) Mexican-American Educators Association, Sacramento, CA, E 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - (4) Language Diversity, Gross National Product cnd Civil Strife (Sony, Stonybrook), E, IIIA/7/1 1988, (audiocassette) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - (1) Yiddish - TV Program, E/Y 1988, (video cassette) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - (1) Linguistic Heterogeneity, Civil Strife and Gross National Product, Stanford U, CA, E, IIIA/7/1 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - (2) Linguistic Heterogeneity, Civil Strife and Gross National Product, Stanford U, CA, E, IIIA/7/1 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - (3) How Yiddish Differs, University of London, E, IIIA/4/31 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - (4) Presentation to JAF of the first issue of The Beacon at the Fryske Academy, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands, E 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - (1) The Irish Language in a Changing Society, E, IIIA/5/9 1989, (video cassette) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - (1) Interview with a Frisian Journalist, Leeuwarden, Friesland, E 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (2) How Yiddish Differs, E, IIIA/4/311989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (3) Reversing Language Shift, E 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (4) YIDISSHE NESIYES, Y 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (5) The Irish Language in a Changing Society: A Sociological Perspective, Dublin, Ireland, E, IIIA/5/9 1989, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (6) Reversing Language Shift: Successes, Disappointments, Doubts and Dilemmas, E, IIIA/9/25 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - (1) Towards a Theory of Reversing Langage Shift, E, IIIA/11/15 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (2) Hebrew in America, E 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (3) Reversing Language Shift, E, IIIA/9/24 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (4) Bilingual Special Education for Survival in the 21st Century, E 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (5) VOS HOT HEBREYISH DERGREYKHT IN DI LETSTE HUNDERT YOR?, Y, IIIA/12/6 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (6) JAF (SHIKLS) 64 GEBURTSTOG-SIMKHE, Y/E 1990, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - (1) 65th Birthday Greetings from Bilingual Students FGS/YU, E/Sp 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - (1) Putting the "Socio" Back in the Sociology of Language, E, IIIA/9/11 1991, (video cassette) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - (1) Reversing Language Shift, E, IIIA/9/24 1991, (video cassette) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - (1) JAF (SHIKLS) GEBURTSTOG-SIMKHE IN SHOLEM ALEYKHEM SHUL, BX, NY, Y 1991, (video cassette) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - (1) JAF (SHIKL) FORZITSER: ITSIK GOTESMAN RETVEGN YUD RAYMER, Y 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - (2) Limits of Ethnolinguistic Democracy, E, IIIA/6/22 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - (1) Reversing Language Shift, E, IIIA/9/24 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (2) REDIFES AF YIDISH, Y, IIIA/9/17 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (3) SOL on the Horizon - Symposiuim in Honor of JAF - JAF Summaries, E 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (4) SOL on the Horizon - Putting the "Socio" in the Sociology of Language, E 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (5) "Language International" Interview, E 1991, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (6) JAF NABE Honoree, E, IIIA/8/8 1992, (audiocassette) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Series 4 J. A. Fishman Course Outlines and Notes 1935-1993
  Materials in this series include course outlines, lecture notes, exams, announcements, background source materials by other colleagues, clippings, and statistical tables. This series is bilingual (English/Yiddish) and includes material relating both to courses given and courses taken by Dr. Fishman. It is divided into three subseries. - Subseries A Courses Given contains information on courses taught by Dr. Fishman at Adelphi University, City College, Columbia University, Harvard University, Hebrew University, San Francisco State, Sholem Aleichem Shul 21 (Bronx, NY, 1948-1950), the University of Hawaii, the University of New Mexico, the University of Pennsylvania, Upper Darby Jr. High School (Philadelphia, 1948), Yeshiva College, and Yeshiva University. It includes a large amount of material on a course called "Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care." - Subseries B Summer Institutes is organized by date and includes information on summer courses taught by Dr. Fishman at Indiana University, Bloomington; Philippine Normal College (the Philippines); Harvard University; Columbia University; the University of Hawaii, Honolulu; the University of Illinois; Adelphi University; the University of San Francisco; the University of New Mexico; Yeshiva University; Stanford University; and Monash University (Australia). It contains a large amount of material on a course entitled "Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities," which Dr. Fishman taught both at Yeshiva University and at Stanford. - Subseries C Courses Taken is organized by date.
  - Subseries A Courses Given
    - General Information Pertaining to JAF Courses at Yeshiva University (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Information Pertaining to JAF Courses at Yeshiva University (Cont'd.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bilingualism and Bilingual Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bilingualism and Bilingual Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Cont'd.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - JAF Comments on Work of Students (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - JAF Comments on Work of Students (Cont'd. 1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - JAF Comments on Work of Students (Cont'd. 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - JAF Comments on Work of Students (Cont'd. 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Communication and Language in Human Relations (University of Pennsylvania) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - History of Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Introduction to the Sociology of Jewish Languages (Yeshiva University) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to the Sociology of Jewish Languages (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Introduction to the Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Seminar in Language and Behavior: Language and Ethnicity (Yeshiva University) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Advanced Seminar in Language and Behavior (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Advanced Seminar in Language and Behavior: Societal Bilingualism - The Sociology of Yiddish (Yeshiva University) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Advanced Seminar in Language and Behavior: Societal Bilingualism - The Sociology of Yiddish (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Advanced Seminar in Language and Behavior: Bilingualism and Biculturalism: Societal Perspectives (Yeshiva University) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Seminar in Language and Behavior - Tests and Measurement in Psycholinguistics (Yeshiva University) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Language and Ethnicity: Jewish and General Perspectives (Yeshiva University) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift (The Case of Spanish in the USA in International Sociolinguistic Perspective (Yeshiva University) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Language, National Identity and Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Language, National Identity and Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Language, National Identity and Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Language, National Identity and Education in Sociolinguistic Perspective (Hebrew University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Linguistics (Columbia University) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 4) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 5) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 6) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 7) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 8) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 9) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - PH. D. Program in Bilingual Educational - Developmental Psychology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 10) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Preparing Research Proposals (Yeshiva University) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Psychology (City College - CCNY) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Psychometric Methods (Yeshiva University) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Religious Beliefs and Values in Health Behavior (Yeshiva University) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Research Methods I (for Clinical Ph.D. Students) (Yeshiva University) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Research Methods I (for Clinical Ph.D. Students) (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Research Methods I & II (for Clinical Ph.D. Students) (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Self-Maintenance Patterns of American Minority Groups (University of Pennsylvania) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Social Psychology (City College - CCNY) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Social Psychology (City College - CCNY) Cont'd. 1) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Social Psychology (City College - CCNY) Cont'd. 2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Social Psychology (City College - CCNY) Cont'd. 3) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Medical Anthropology (Yeshiva University) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Medical Anthropology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Medical Anthropology (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Basic Introductory Concepts (Yeshiva University) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Traditional Folk Medicines and their approach to Health Care (Yeshiva University) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Traditional Folk Medicines and their approach to Health Care (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Contact between Traditional and Modern Western Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Contact between Traditional and Modern Western Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Contact between Traditional and Modern Western Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: The Sick Role/Experience of Illness (Yeshiva University) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: The Sick Role/Experience of Illness (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Doctor-Patient Relations (Yeshiva University) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Doctor-Patient Relations (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Doctor-Patient Relations (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Doctor-Patient Relations (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Blacks (Yeshiva University) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Blacks (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Cubans (Yeshiva University) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Haitian Americans (Yeshiva University) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 4) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 5) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 6) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Hispanics (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 7) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Mexican-Americans (Yeshiva University) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 4) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 5) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 6) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 7) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 8) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Sociocultural Factors in Health and Health Care: Religion as Medicine (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 9) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Sociology of Bilingual Education (Hebrew University) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Sociology of Bilingual Education (Yeshiva University, University of Hawaii, Harvard, San Francisco State, University of New Mexico) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Sociology of Bilingual Education (Yeshiva University, University of Hawaii, Harvard, San Francisco State, University of New Mexico) (Cont'd.) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 1) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 2) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 3) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 4) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Sociology of Language (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd. 5) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Sociology of Language/Sociolinguistics (Yeshiva University) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sociology of Religion (Yeshiva University) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sociology of Yiddish: 19th Century (Yeshiva University) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Sociology of Yiddish: 19th Century (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Statistics: A Non-Mathematical Introduction to Factor-Analysis (City College - CCNY) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Statistics: A Non-Mathematical Introduction to Factor-Analysis (City College - CCNY) (Cont'd.) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - JAF Student Teaching "Social Studies" (Upper Darby Jr. High School, Phila., PA 1948) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - JAF Student Teaching "Social Studies" (Upper Darby Jr. High School, Phila., PA 1948) (Cont'd.) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Survey of Research Findings in Bilingual Education (Yeshiva University) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Techniques of Social Research (Yeshiva University) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Test Construction: Theories and Methods (Yeshiva University) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Test Construction: Theories and Methods (Yeshiva University) (Cont'd.) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish Courses at Yiddish Secular School: Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Yiddish Courses at Yiddish Secular School: Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY (Cont'd. 1) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish Courses at Yiddish Secular School: Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY (Cont'd. 2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish Courses at Yiddish Secular School: Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY (Cont'd. 3) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish and Yiddishism in the 19th and early 20th Centuries (Yeshiva University) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Sociology of Language - Course Readings (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sociology of Language - FGS/YU Spring 1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sociology of Language - Summer 1978, Urbana, IL and Spring 1977, Yeshiva College, 1977-78 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Sociology of Language - AdelphiSummer 1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sociology of Language - various times and places (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care:Course Organization (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care:Course Organization (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Organization (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care:Course Organization (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Films (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Films (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: General Readings, Socio-cultural and ethno. factors (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care:General Readings, Socio-cultural and ethno. factors (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care:General Readings (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Course Reading Material 1-3 by weekly sessions (Box 19, Folder 1)